Balaji J

Data Enginee

Data Engineer with 3 years of experience in offering dedication to deliver effective technical solutions with strong mindset of learning new technologies, exponential upgradation of Skillset, good critical thinking & problem solving skills, Also self-motivated and capable enough in analyzing huge data to capture meaningful insights to solve business problems along with ample hands-on experience of data analysis using SQL ETL operations and PowerBI dashboard building skilled with developing data pipelines using tools like Data factory and Apache Kafka.

Malajigowdaj23@gmail.com

^o Chennai, India

github.com/Balaji-Gowda

9701660072

in linkedin.com/in/balaji-j-msc

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst Trimble Inc.

06/2022 - Present

Chennai

ViewPoint Analytics

- ERP Data transfer from SQL cloud database to Snowflake data cloud in JSON format through Kafka connectors.
- Performing ETL on raw Kafka topics using SQL in various levels and storing the data in tabular format.
- Applying data mining and transforming data to business relevant output using complex SQL queries automated with Snowflake Streams and Tasks and storing as Views.
- Projecting Views to Power BI and visualizing the Constructional data with multiple KPI's and charts built using DAX to provide insights for Users about their customers and field workers which are then deployed to final portal via PowerBI server.
- Implemented a chatbot for Analytics users to access ERP documentation content with ease that built using Python, NLP transformers and flask framework.

Programmer Analyst

Cognizant Technology Solutions

12/2020 - 06/2022

Bangalore

Philips Sales Solutions

- Performed ETL operations using Azure Data Factory and Databricks.
- worked for Price List Generation Automated Project.
- Developed Data models using QlikView.
- Worked in designing UI for Bundling Simulation using Python and Django.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology

Madanapalle

07/2016 - 09/2020

9.01

Courses

 Electronics and Communication Engineering

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Capstone Project:

 A Machine Learning project to predict bank customers' status of loan and to group them into clusters based on certain features using K-Means clustering & Random Forest Classifier algorithms to help banks know about their customers and act accordingly to get better profits and created, deployed Python Streamlit Web App on Heroku cloud.

Spam SMS Classifier:

 A Machine Learning & Natural Language Processing based project that classifies input message as SPAM or HAM using Naive Bayes classifier to reduce the risk of system hack which was created with Flask Web App and deployed on Heroku cloud.

Car Price Prediction:

 A Machine Learning project to predict price of used cars so as to help sellers in fixing cost on the basis of various qualities and parameters using Linear regression Algorithm and deployed Flask Web App on Heroku cloud.

LANGUAGES

Telugu

English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

Tamil

Limited Working Proficiency

HINGI

y Limited Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Web Surfing

Coding

Cooking